Guide to the Socialist Party (U.S.) New York (N.Y.) Letter Books TAM.056.005
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Socialist Party (U.S.) New York (N.Y.) Letter Books
1907-1914
1911-1914
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Socialist Party of New York
TAM.056.005
2.5 Linear Feet (6 boxes)
The New York City local was the largest such unit of the Socialist Party (U.S.). The collection consists of 151 subject files that include correspondence, reports on electoral activities, membership records, branch records, committee papers, financial papers, minutes, form letters, miscellaneous printed matter, resolutions, and convention reports. Note: this collection has been microfilmed, and researchers must use the microfilm copy (R-7124, reels 6-8).
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Due to the fragile nature of the original materials, researchers must use the microfilmed version; microfilm call number is Film R-7124, Reels 6-8.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the Rand School Archives, 1963. The accession number associated with this collection is 1963.019.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
The New York City local was the largest and most significant such unit of the Socialist Party (U.S.), and its membership included many individuals also involved in the leadership of the national organization.
Scope and Content Note
The Socialist Party (U.S.) New York (N.Y.) Letter Books, 1907-1914 (titled, on the microfilm as the "Socialist Party (U.S.) Local New York Letter Books"), are organized into 151 subject files, many of which contain no more than 30 items. The bulk of the collection pertains to the activities of the New York City local of the Socialist Party for the years, 1911 1914. There are, however, some items at the beginning of the collection that pertain to the period, 1907 1910. The types of materials in this collection include correspondence, reports on electoral activities, membership records, branch records, committee papers, financial papers, minutes, form letters, miscellaneous printed matter, resolutions, and convention reports. Each subject file has been given a frame number and has been cited in the complete reel list that follows this description of the arrangement of the collection. The researcher should also note that an error was made in the targeting for this collection. On each frame, the word "Series" appears adjacent to the frame number. This term should actually be interpreted as "Collection".
The subject files are first arranged chronologically by year and then alphabetically within the year. Those files with a single letter ("A") or letter group designation ("H K") relate to the general correspondence of the New York City local. These correspondence files which were organized alphabetically according to the last name of the recipient of the letter or the author of the letter, precede specific subject files with the same alphabetical designation. Thus, the "B" correspondence file for 1911 precedes the "Branches" subject file in the arrangement of the collection. Following the alphabetical arrangement, the items within the subject files are arranged in chronological order. In some instances, the items within a file do not correspond exactly to the year in which they were originally placed in the collection. For example, the Grievance Committee records for 1914 (V:115) include items for both 1913 and 1915. Fortunately, this circumstance occurs only in several files for 1913 and 1914.
Most of the subject files in this collection contain information about such routine party operations as scheduling lectures and rallies, planning meetings and special events, processing applications for membership, handling literature requests, and recording membership dues. In addition to these matters, the collection contains considerable information about a variety of events and issues which concerned socialists during the pre World War I period. Some of these events discussed in the subject files include the socialist Party's support for the Mexican Revolution, the expulsion of William Haywood from the Socialist Party's National Executive Committee, the Paterson silk workers strike, the New York City garment workers strike, Margaret Sanger's work as an organizer for the Women's Agitation Committee, the Socialist Party's support for municipal ownership of vital public services industries, the Socialist Party's opposition to the Dillingham immigration restriction bill, the ouster of Gustavus Myers from the New York City local, the 1912 Presidential campaign, the resignations of W. E. B. DuBois and Walter Lippmann from the Socialist Party, the socialist response to the outbreak of war in Europe, the 1911 Triangle Shirt Waist Company fire, and the 1914 New York City Unemployment Conference. Among the prominent socialists who participated in these events and who have significant correspondence in this collection are Fred Arland, Victor Berger, W. J. Ghent, Julius Gerber, J. Mahlon Barnes, Eugene V. Debs, Charles Edward Russell, Harry W. Laidler, Margaret Sanger, W. E. B. DuBois, Walter Uppmann, John M. Work, Fred D. Warren, Florence Kelley, Jessie Ashley, James H. Maurer, and Gustavus Myers.
One of the most interesting files in the collection relates to the Lawrence, Massachusetts, textile workers strike of 1912 (V:44). The types of materials contained in this file include correspondence, status reports on the strike, donation and financial reports, resolutions, and mimeographed letters. Much of this material pertains to the Socialist Party's fund raising activities on behalf of the Lawrence strikers, particularly Joseph Ettor and Arturo Giovannitti who were charged with first-degree murder during the strike. Other items of importance in this file include several letters from Joseph Ettor to Julius Gerber and a letter from Dudley Hohnan, secretary to Governor Eugene N. Foss, to Julius Gerber in which Hohnan defends the police actions during the strike.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged chronologically by year, and alphabetically within each year.
The files are grouped into 1 series:
Missing Title
Inventory
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Socialist Party of New York State. Records.
Socialist collections in the Tamiment Library, 1872-1956: a guide to the microfilm edition (Sanford, N.C.: Microfilming Corp. of America, c1979), 181 p.
Socialism -- United States.; Socialism -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Labor disputes -- New York (State) -- New York.; Silk Workers' Strike, Paterson, N.J., 1913.; Lawrence (Mass.); Minutes (administrative records); Russell, Charles Edward, 1860-1941; Myers, Gustavus, 1872-1942; Maurer, James H. (James Hudson), b. 1864.; Lippmann, Walter, 1889-1974.; Warren, Fred D., 1872 or 3-1959; Triangle Shirtwaist Company; Work, John M. (John McClelland), 1869-1961.; Sanger, Margaret, 1879-1966; Laidler, Harry W. (Harry Wellington), 1884-1970; Ettor, Joseph J.; Du Bois, W. E. B. (William Edward Burghardt), 1868-1963; Debs, Eugene V. (Eugene Victor), 1855-1926; Berger, Victor L., 1860-1929; Kelley, Florence, 1859-1932; Giovannitti, Arturo M., 1884-1959; Ghent, William J. (William James), 1866-1942.; Barnes, John Mahlon, 1886-1934
- Inventory
  - Fragments, Nov 18, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:1
  - Fragments, Jul 29, 1908, Sep 8, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:2
  - Fragments, Sep 1, 1908-Sep 1, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:3
  - Fragments, Jun 22, 1910-Sep 1, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:4
  - "A", Feb 18, 1911-Nov 1, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:5
  - "B", Feb 2, 1911-Dec 30, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:6
  - Branches, Jun 7, 1911-Nov 25, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:7
  - "C-G', Feb 18, 1911-Dec 30, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:8
  - Campaign, Jun 23, 1911-Dec 21, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:9
  - Elections, Mar 7, 1911-Nov 7, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:10
  - "H-K", Feb 2, 1911-Oct 11, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:11
  - Irish Socialist Federation, Aug 1, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:12
  - "L-N", Feb 6, 1911-Dec 22, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:13
  - Labor Unions, Feb 14, 1911-Nov 23, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:14
  - May Day 1911, May 1, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:15
  - Mexico, Apr 3, 1911-Jun 5, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:16
  - Milwaukee, May 11, 1911-Jul 1, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:17
  - Minutes, Sep 17, 1911-Dec 17, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:18
  - National, May 9, 1911-Aug 14, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:19
  - Police Department, Mar 6, 1911-Dec 23, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:20
  - "R", Jul 7, 1911-Oct 13, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:21
  - Resolutions, Jun 7, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:22
  - "S", Jan 26, 1911-Dec 30, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:23
  - Sanger, Margaret, Nov 8, 1911-Dec 30, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:24
  - State, Jan 1, 1911-Dec 18, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:25
  - Subways, Apr 30, 1911-Jul 18, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:26
  - "T-V", Mar 8, 1911-Dec 19, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:27
  - "W", Feb 25, 1911-Dec 18, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:28
  - Women's Committee, Feb 15, 1911-Dec 18, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:29
  - "Y-Z", Oct 3, 1911-Dec 30, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:30
  - "A-Z", Jan 4, 1912-Dec 30, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:31
  - Branches, Jan 22, 1912-Dec 24, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:32
  - Branches: Jewish, Feb 26, 1912-Dec 18, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:33
  - Central Committee, Oct 1, 1912-Dec 1, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:34
  - Central Federated Union, Feb 1, 1912-Jul 13, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:35
  - Country Committee, May 8, 1912-Dec 1, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:36
  - Elections: Correspondence, Jan 26, 1912-Dec 2, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:37
  - Elections: Minutes of Committees, Feb 12, 1912-Nov 1, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:38
  - Elections: Miscellaneous, Jan 1, 1912-Nov 5, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Film R-7124, Reel 6; Frame V:39
  - Financial, May 1, 1912-Dec 31, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:40
  - General Committee, Mar 26, 1905 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:41
  - Immigration, May 4, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:42
  - Labor Unions, Apr 13, 1912-Nov 14, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:43
  - Lawrence Strike, Jan 31, 1912-Nov 22, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:44
  - Lectures, Oct 1, 1912-Mar 1, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:45
  - May Day 1912, Mar 18, 1912-May 3, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:46
  - Myers, Gustavus, Jun 22, 1911-Dec 11, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:47
  - National, Jan 1, 1912-Jun 28, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:48
  - National, Jul 15, 1912-Dec 29, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:49
  - Police Department, Apr 9, 1912-Sep 30, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:50
  - Progressive Party, Oct 7, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:51
  - State, Feb 7, 1912-Dec 28, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:52
  - Triangle Fire, Feb 21, 1911-Jul 29, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:53
  - Women's Committee, Feb 3, 1912-Nov 12, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:54
  - "A", Jul 12, 1911, Feb 27, 1913-Dec 30, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:55
  - Advertising, Oct 31, 1911 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:56
  - Agreements, Oct 21, 1911-Feb 9, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:57
  - "B", Feb 15, 1912-Dec 31, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:58
  - Branches, Feb 21, 1913-Dec 18, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:59
  - Branches: 1-4, Jan 22, 1913-Dec 29, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:60
  - Branches: 5-14, Sep 28, 1911-Oct 5, 1911, Jun 1, 1912-Dec 26, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:61
  - Branches: Bohemian-Slovak, Jan 4, 1913-Dec 24, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:62
  - "C", Jan 11, 1913-Dec 19, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:63
  - Campaign, Apr 21, 1913-Aug 22, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:64
  - Campaign, Aug 25, 1913-Dec 26, 1913, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:65
  - "D-E", Feb 5, 1913-Dec 29, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:66
  - "F-G", Apr 24, 1913-Jun 16, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:67
  - Garment Workers Strike, Jan 1, 1913-Jun 16, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:68
  - Grievance Committee, Jan 3, 1913-Oct 28, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:69
  - "H-P", Apr 21, 1913-Dec 18, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:70
  - Platform, Apr 17, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:71
  - Referendums and Resolutions, Jan 3, 1913-Dec 28, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:72
  - Resignations, Nov 6, 1912, Mar 13, 1913-Oct 13, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:73
  - "S-W", Jan 28, 1913-Dec 13, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:74
  - "A", Jan 13, 1914-Dec 18, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:75
  - Anti-War Demonstration, Aug 6, 1914-Aug 13, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:76
  - Ashley, Jessie, Feb 10, 1914-Feb 28, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:77
  - "B", Feb 12, 1914-Dec 29, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Film R-7124, Reel 7; Frame V:78
  - Ballots, Sample, Mar 28, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Ball of Local New York, Feb 3, 1914-Dec 6, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:79
  - Board of Elections, Feb 2, 1914-Oct 21, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:80
  - Branches: Circular Letters, Apr 4, 1914-Dec 24, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:81
  - Branches: 3rd and 10th Assembly Districts, Apr 11, 1914-Dec 24, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:82
  - Branch: 6th Assembly District, Jul 13, 1914-Aug 18, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:83
  - Branches: 9th, 11th, 13th, and 29th Assembly Districts, Feb 14, 1914-Sep 5, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:84
  - Branches: 12th and 14th assembly Districts, Nov 18, 1914-Dec 4, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:85
  - Branch: 19th Assembly District, Jan 19, 1914-Oct 2, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:86
  - Branch: 21st Assembly District, Jan 23, 1914-Jun 25, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:87
  - Branch: 23rd Assembly District, Aug 10, 1914-Dec 15, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:88
  - Branches: 25th and 27th Assembly Districts, Apr 2, 1914-Oct 27, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:89
  - Branch: 26TH Assembly District, Apr 1, 1914-Sep 29, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:90
  - Branches: German, Mar 28, 1914-Nov 30, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:91
  - Branches: Jewish, May 7, 1914-Dec 22, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:92
  - Branches: Lettish, Mar 17, 1914-Nov 24, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:93
  - Branch: Scandinavian, May 28, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:94
  - "C", Jan 19, 1914-Dec 24, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:95
  - Calumet, Michigan Strike, Oct 27, 1913-Jan 30, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:96
  - Campaign Committee: 12th Congressional District, Dec 15, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:97
  - Carnegie Hall, Apr 22, 1914-Apr 27, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:98
  - Cassidy, Edward F., Mar 28, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:99
  - Circular Letters, Jan 5, 1914-Jul 9, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:100
  - County Committee, Mar 28, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:101
  - Contributions for Colorado Miners, Jan 3, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:102
  - "D", May 5, 1914-Aug 31, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:103
  - Debbs, Eugene V., Jul 3, 1914-Jul 30, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:104
  - Designation Petitions, Mar 28, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:105
  - Direct Primaries, Mar 28, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:106
  - Dues, Apr 1, 1914-Nov 18, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:107
  - Elections, Aug 21, 1914-Nov 1, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:108
  - "F", Jan 26, 1912-Dec 22, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:109
  - Harry Feldman Fund, Nov 19, 1914-Dec 7, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:110
  - Financial, 1911-1913 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:111
  - Finnish Branch, Sep 12, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:112
  - Free-Lancing, Aug 26, 1914-Sep 4, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:113
  - "G", Mar 30, 1914-Dec 3, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:114
  - Grievance Committee, Aug 29, 1913-Jan 5, 1915 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:115
  - "H", Jan 30, 1914-Dec 10, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:116
  - Harrison-Urban Debate: 3rd and 10th Assembly Districts, Mar 24, 1914-Jan 6, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:117
  - Hillquit Lectures, Oct 22, 1914-Jan 9, 1915 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:118
  - Investigations Committee, Dec 31, 1913-Jan 2, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:119
  - Immigration Bill (proposed amendments), Dec 16, 1913-Dec 24, 1913, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:120
  - Irving Place Theater Performance, Mar 19, 1914-Apr 14, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:121
  - "J-L", Jan 2, 1914-Dec 22, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:122
  - Locals, Mar 3, 1914-Dec 15, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:123
  - "M", Mar 3, 1914-Dec 3, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:124
  - Mat Day Parade 1914, Mar 25, 1914-May 12, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:125
  - Charles Milich (502 Broadway) Grievance, Oct 10, 1913-Mar 2, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:126
  - Murray Hill Lyceum Meeting, May 11, 1914-May 18, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:127
  - "N", Jul 11, 1913-Oct 22, 1914, undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:128
  - National Office (Socialist Party), Jan 26, 1914-Jan 1, 1915 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:129
  - Nominations for Public Office, Jul 27, 1914-Jul 28, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:130
  - "O", Jan 4, 1914-Mar 1, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:131
  - Organization Committee, Mar 7, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:132
  - "P", Jun 24, 1914-Jul 14, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:133
  - Parks, Commissioner of (permits for meetings), Apr 14, 1914-Aug 6, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:134
  - Police, Commissioner of, Jul 31, 1914-Aug 11, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:135
  - Primary Days, Sep 28, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:136
  - Propaganda, Committee on, Apr 14, 1914-Apr 15, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:137
  - "R", May 20, 1914-Oct 30, 1914 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:138
  - Rand School, Sep 16, 1914-Nov 5, 1914 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:139
  - Red Week, Aug 19, 1914-Sep 5, 1914 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:140
  - Referendums, Nov 3, 1913-Jun 2, 1914 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:141
  - Resignations, Nov 3, 1914 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:142
  - Resolutions Adopted by the Party, Mar 16, 1914-Apr 8, 1914 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:143
  - Speakers, Feb 11, 1914 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:144
  - State Committee, Mar 3, 1914-Jan 8, 1915 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:145
  - State Convention: Local New York, Feb 9, 1914-Jun 30, 1914 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:146
  - Unemployment Conference, Jan 21, 1914-Feb 22, 1914 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:147
  - Unemployment Demonstration, Mar 14, 1914-Mar 23, 1914 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:148
  - War Emergency Labor Conference, Sep 2, 1914-Oct 21, 1914 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:149
  - Watchers on Elections, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:150
  - "X-Z", Jan 6, 1914-Sep 1, 1914 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    Film R-7124, Reel 8; Frame V:151